In a dark and hidden part of Colombia, there was a man whose actions were so terrible that
they are hard to believe.
His name was Luis Alfredo Garavito Cubillos, but he was better known as La Bestia or The
Beast.
His life was marked by a series of horrifying crimes, some of the worst in recent history.
Born on January 25, 1957, into a family where he faced a lot of abuse and neglect, Garavito's
early years were filled with suffering, which he later inflicted on others.
Growing up in Ceylan, Garavito had a very hard childhood.
His father was abusive, and at school he was constantly teased and called Garabato because
he wore glasses.
He felt alienated and alone, and this isolation was made worse by a terrible incident of abuse
by a local pharmacist.
These experiences filled him with deep anger and a desire for revenge against a world that
had treated him so harshly.
The 1980s were the beginning of his dreadful crimes.
He targeted Colombia's most vulnerable children, those who were poor, orphaned, or homeless.
He would first gain their trust by offering them small jobs or gifts, then he would take
them to hidden places where he committed shocking acts of cruelty.
He would tie them up, hurt them, and kill them with such brutality that it caused nationwide
horror.
Garavito found perverse pleasure in these acts and meticulously recorded them as if
keeping a journal of pain and death.
For nearly two decades, Garavito moved from one city to another, changing his appearance
and taking on different roles, from priests to teachers, to avoid capture.
The Colombian police, already struggling with other national problems, found it difficult
to connect the cases of missing children to him, even as the number of cases grew.
It wasn't until 1999, after he tried to attack a boy named John Ivan Sabagal, that
the police began to piece together the evidence that would lead to his capture.
This marked the beginning of the end of his reign of terror.
When arrested, Garavito confessed to the murder of 147 children.
His trial resulted in the longest sentence in Colombian history, 1,853 years in prison.
However, due to legal limits he could only serve a maximum of 40 years.
His case shocked both the nation and the world, generating a massive outcry over how such
evil could have gone unnoticed for so long.
Garavito died of cancer in prison in October 2023.
His death brought little solace to the Colombian people, who still live with the painful memories
of his crimes.
The story of his life is a chilling reminder of the darkness that can exist within the
human heart.
His tale ends with a warning to everyone.
Stay safe, stay vigilant.
This message highlights that evil is relentless, and once innocence is lost, it can never
be fully regained.
This narrative serves not only as a recount of his crimes, but also as a call to maintain
vigilance and protect the vulnerable in society.
It reminds us that the cost of overlooking such evil is too great, a lesson that remains
relevant beyond the borders of Colombia, and continues to resonate globally.